<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kevin Zolea on Kevin Zolea</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kevin Zolea on Kevin Zolea</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;2019 Kevin Zolea</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a website with the academic theme in blogdown</title>
      <link>/post/creating-a-website-with-the-academic-theme-in-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/creating-a-website-with-the-academic-theme-in-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;introduction&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years now I have been contemplating developing my first personal website. I have been told by a countless number of people that it is a great way to showcase your skills and tell your story. I have been meaning to make one for some time now but I kept coming up with excuses. The two biggest excuses I kept telling myself was that it would be too difficult &amp;amp; it would cost money. Boy was I wrong. It wasn’t until I started using R this past year that I realized how wrong I was. After a quick google search I came across the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/blogdown/blogdown.pdf&#34;&gt;blogdown&lt;/a&gt; package. Blogdown is an amazing package in which you can create blogs and websites with &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;R Markdown&lt;/a&gt;. Now I’m not saying that this stuff is extremely easy but if someone like myself(absolutely no website development knowledge) can do it, &lt;strong&gt;YOU CAN TOO!&lt;/strong&gt; This blog post isn’t a sure fire way to do it but more of an overview of how I did it. I would also like to point out that this is a &lt;strong&gt;very basic introduction &lt;/strong&gt; to creating a blog/website with blogdown. The amount of things you can do with this package is almost endless.. especially if you have an understanding of CSS, HTML, and Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/Rl9Yqavfj2Ula/giphy.gif&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;prerequisites&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you jump right in I recommend reading some online material and watching some youtube videos. Here is a list of the resources that helped me a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blogdown: Creating Websites with R Markdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;a href=&#34;https://alison.rbind.io/post/up-and-running-with-blogdown/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Up and Running with Blogdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=syWAKaj-4ck&amp;amp;t=649s&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Making a Website with Blogdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34;&gt;Academic Theme Documentation&lt;/a&gt; (if your going to use the academic theme)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;a href=&#34;https://amber.rbind.io/blog/2016/12/19/creatingsite/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Making a Website Using Blogdown, Hugo, and GitHub pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you review the above material you should have a pretty firm grasp on how to get the ball rolling. One of the biggest hurdles I had was creating my site with the Hugo Academic Theme. It wasn’t until I found this &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/54300535/unable-to-create-new-site-using-hugo-academic-theme&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; on stackoverflow that I was able to figure out what the problem was. There was a breaking change in the hugo-academic theme, so I had to download the development verison of blogdown. Not sure if this is still a thing but if you have the same problem definitly check out that post! The last piece of advice I will give before we get started is to make sure you check what the minimum hugo verision is for the theme you want to use. You can do this by going to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;hugo website&lt;/a&gt;. Pick the theme you want to use and look at the line that says &lt;code&gt;Minimum Hugo Verision:&lt;/code&gt; You can check what verision of hugo you have by using &lt;code&gt;hugo_verison()&lt;/code&gt; in R. Now lets get started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;step-1-create-new-repository-in-github&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Step 1: Create New Repository in GitHub&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to assume you have used &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; before but if you haven’t that is completely fine. You can check out this &lt;a href=&#34;https://guides.github.com/&#34;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; to get a better understanding. Once you have a good understanding of GitHub and have an account created you need to create a new repository. You can name this repository anything you want but it’s usually best practice to give it a meaningful name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the Diurnal Cycle of Precipitation in the NCEP Global Forecast System</title>
      <link>/project/ncep_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ncep_project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Forecasting the diurnal cycle of precipitation over the continental United States (CONUS) is a problematic process for most global forecast systems. A majority tends to have a strong bias and they don’t provide a skilled prediction of the intensity, coverage and frequency of the diurnal cycle. Accurately forecasting the diurnal precipitation cycle, is closely related to the overall quality of the global forecast itself. Also, the accuracy of representation of physical processes in the models is indicative to the forecast skill. Major implementations have been made for the National Center for Environmental Prediction (NCEP) operational Global Forecast System (GFS) throughout the years to make improvements to the diurnal cycle of precipitation. This study examines the diurnal cycle of precipitation over the CONUS during the winter and summer months of 2016-2017. The operational and experimental GFS will be analyzed and compared to the observed diurnal cycle of precipitation. To accomplish this, 3-hourly averaged accumulated precipitation vs. forecast hour plots, for the different models, were created. This allowed us to gain insight on how the skill of the models were performing, against the observations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This study is expected to provide feedback to the model developers at NCEP’s Environmental Modeling Center (EMC) to inform (for making further) priorities for improvements to the GFS model, especially with the newly selected Next Generation Global Prediction System (NGGPS) Finite Volume Cube Sphere (FV3) modeling system. The NGGPS is a fully coupled system that will be designed to create useful forecast guidance out to 30 days, extend forecast skill beyond 8 to 10 days, and improve hurricane track/intensity forecast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study Analysis of Easterly Wave Formation in the East Pacific</title>
      <link>/project/colorado_state_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/colorado_state_project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Easterly waves are weak troughs of low pressure that propagate westward across the Atlantic and East Pacific. These disturbances seed the majority of East Pacific and Atlantic tropical cyclones. Most easterly waves originate from Africa, although recent work indicates that they can also be locally generated in the East Pacific. This study analyzed the development and origins of the two precursor disturbances that eventually became Hurricanes Patricia and John in the East Pacific. Using TRMM precipitation and ERA-I reanalysis datasets, we investigate the local processes responsible for the organization of vorticity and precipitation in the initial disturbances from which these tropical cyclones formed. It is shown that although the easterly wave that formed Hurricane John originated from Africa, interactions with the Gulf of Papagayo jet influenced the intensification of the disturbance. The disturbance that formed Hurricane Patricia strengthened through complex interactions with the Gulf of Tehuantepec wind jet. Our results support the contention that both local and remote influences contribute to easterly wave formation in the East Pacific Ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Page</title>
      <link>/tutorial/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/example/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my top 10 tips for getting started with Academic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1&#34;&gt;Tip 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2&#34;&gt;Tip 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>/talk/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Academic&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further talk details can easily be added to this page using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Person Re-Identification System For Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>/publication/person-re-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/person-re-id/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile visual clothing search</title>
      <link>/publication/clothing-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/clothing-search/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
