<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Kevin Zolea</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Kevin Zolea</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;2019 Kevin Zolea</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips For Customizing Your R Leaflet Map</title>
      <link>/post/r-leaflet/tips-for-customizing-your-r-leaflet-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-leaflet/tips-for-customizing-your-r-leaflet-map/</guid>
      <description>OverviewMaps are apart of our everyday lifes. They can be seen in almost every industry and are useful for numerous different purposes. A lot of the time these maps are static. Sometimes, however, it’s extremely useful to interact with the data on the map. This is where the Leaflet package comes in. This post will go over what the Leaflet package is and provide some useful tips on how to make your new interactive map shine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the USGS dataRetrieval package to analyze continuous water quality data</title>
      <link>/post/usgs/using-the-usgs-dataretrieval-package-to-analyze-water-quality-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/usgs/using-the-usgs-dataretrieval-package-to-analyze-water-quality-trends/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionBeing that I work for the Division of Water Monitoring &amp;amp; Standards, I have to analyze a lot of water quality data. A majority of the data is in house from the samples we collect but most times I have to download data from online sources. These online sources usually consist of the same organizations and most have a pretty straight forward way of getting access to the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a website with the academic theme in blogdown</title>
      <link>/post/blogdown/creating-a-website-with-the-academic-theme-in-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/blogdown/creating-a-website-with-the-academic-theme-in-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:I have been told by a countless number of people that creating a personal website is a great way to showcase your skills and tell your story. I have been contemplating this for some time but kept procrastinating. The two biggest excuses I kept telling myself was that it would be too difficult &amp;amp; it would cost money. Boy was I wrong! It wasn’t until I started using R this past year that I realized how wrong I was.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>