<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meteorology on Kevin Zolea</title>
    <link>/tags/meteorology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meteorology on Kevin Zolea</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;2019 Kevin Zolea</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/meteorology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the Diurnal Cycle of Precipitation in the NCEP Global Forecast System</title>
      <link>/project/ncep_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ncep_project/</guid>
      <description>Forecasting the diurnal cycle of precipitation over the continental United States (CONUS) is a problematic process for most global forecast systems. A majority tends to have a strong bias and they don’t provide a skilled prediction of the intensity, coverage and frequency of the diurnal cycle. Accurately forecasting the diurnal precipitation cycle, is closely related to the overall quality of the global forecast itself. Also, the accuracy of representation of physical processes in the models is indicative to the forecast skill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study Analysis of Easterly Wave Formation in the East Pacific</title>
      <link>/project/colorado_state_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/colorado_state_project/</guid>
      <description>Easterly waves are weak troughs of low pressure that propagate westward across the Atlantic and East Pacific. These disturbances seed the majority of East Pacific and Atlantic tropical cyclones. Most easterly waves originate from Africa, although recent work indicates that they can also be locally generated in the East Pacific. This study analyzed the development and origins of the two precursor disturbances that eventually became Hurricanes Patricia and John in the East Pacific.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>